Rógvi Dávid Arge

Data Science & Optimization Consultant

Phone: +45 5042 5002

E-mail: argeinnovations@gmail.com

LinkedIn: http://dk.linkedin.com/in/rogvidarge/en

GitHub: https://github.com/rogvid



SUMMARY

Data Scientist with more than 4 years of experience in agile project development and a passion for deep learning, predictive analytics and optimization. Vast experience in data wrangling, exploratory data analysis, machine learning and data visualization and applying these skills to generate corporate wide improvements.

EXPERIENCE

Arge Innovations | Owner & Data Science Consultant Dec. 2018 - Present Agile development and deployment of data science, and optimization products.

DFDS A/S (Contract) | Data Science Consultant Dec. 2018 - May. 2019 Initialized a revolution of the transportation & logistics industry by:

- \bullet Helping reduce RMSE of prediction algorithm by 20% and implementing a number of scalable machine learning model
- Enabling a completely new transportation planning paradigm by implementing optimization tool that visualized plans to users

ATP= | Data Scientist

Feb. 2017 - Dec. 2018

- Decreased prediction failures caused by server downtime by building a Flask based server/database monitoring system
- Enabled investigation of people with complex fraud patterns by implementing a hybrid machine learning expert system model
- \bullet Reduced payments of social benefits to fraudulent people by more than 10 mio. using expert systems

ConWX | Programmer & Data Analyst

Apr. 2015 - Feb. 2017

- \bullet Greatly increased one of our largest clients monthly revenue by discovering a way to improve our forecasts by 18%
- Designed and developed a monitoring system essential for forecast quality assurance and improvement

Udacity Data Analyst Nanodegree Project Explore and Summarize Data

Feb. 2016

Scraped Boliga.dk and income statistics for people in Copenhagen. EDA showed an explosive increase in appartment prices around 500%, as well as the effects of the economic crisis on declining size of raises.

• Python • R • MongoDB • EDA • Data Wrangling

EDUCATION

Copenhagen University | M.Sc. in Physics

2012 - 2015

Focus on computational physics, machine learning and mathematical modeling.

Copenhagen University | B.Sc. in Physics

2009 - 2012

Focus on laser physics, optics, and quantum mechanics.

CERTIFICATIONS

Coursera | Deep Learning Specialization

2018

Development of deep learning models in Tensorflow & Keras. Specialization taught by Andrew Ng on Coursera.

Udacity | Data Analyst Nanodegree

2015 - 2017

Project based courses teaching essential knowledge and skills for data scientists.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python Machine Learning Optimization Operations Research Data Visualization Data Analysis Modeling Statistics Git SQL D3HTML CSS JavaScript C#Docker AWS Azure MongoDB

SOFT SKILLS

Problem Solving
Critical Thinking
Communication
Adaptability
Project Planning
Decision Making
Scrum

LANGUAGES

Native speaker

Faroese Danish

ciency

Professional proficiency
English

Elementary proficiency

Norwegian Swedish French

